Guide to the Gabriel family papers, 1916-1925.
Gabriel family papers, 1916-1925.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Gabriel family papers, 1916-1925.
2482
Gabriel family.
.3 cubic ft.
Correspondence, military papers, photographs, and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The collection includes primarily the papers of Harry S. Gabriel including letters to his mother and fiancee, Ellen Wigsten, depicting daily life before and after the armistice, written from American training camps and the French front, his war diary (October - November 1918) describing night patrols, documents relating to his military service and awards, photographs of Gabriel in uniform and of Camp Dix, New Jersey, and related printed matter, including an orientation pamphlet titled "France Our Ally" (1918); also Gabriel's letters from England (1919) giving impressions of the country and describing life at Oxford University, his travels in England, and his farm observations near Oxford, letters (1916-1918) in French to Miss Wigsten from a Belgian soldier, containing scattered references to the war, and other subjects.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Harry S. Gabriel served as 1st Lieutenant in the American Expeditionary Forces, where he saw combat with the 316th Infantry. After the war, he studied agriculture at Oxford University.
He graduated with the Cornell University Class of 1915 and received his M.S. in 1920 and his Ph.D. in 1925.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The collection includes primarily the papers of Harry S. Gabriel including letters to his mother and fiancee, Ellen Wigsten, depicting daily life before and after the armistice, written from American training camps and the French front, his war diary (October - November 1918) describing night patrols, documents relating to his military service and awards, photographs of Gabriel in uniform and of Camp Dix, New Jersey, and related printed matter, including an orientation pamphlet titled "France Our Ally" (1918); also Gabriel's letters from England (1919) giving impressions of the country and describing life at Oxford University, his travels in England, and his farm observations near Oxford, letters (1916-1918) in French to Miss Wigsten from a Belgian soldier, containing scattered references to the war, and other subjects.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Gabriel family.; Gabriel, Harry S., 1892-1959.; Kaufman, Nestor.; Wigsten, Ellen Cecilia,; United States.Army.American Expeditionary Forces.Infantry Regiment, 316th.; United States.Army--Military life.; University of Oxford.
Subjects:
World War, 1914-1918--Personal narratives, American.; World War, 1914-1918--Personal narratives, Belgian.
Places:
England--Description and travel.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Nestor Kaufmoy Letters (in French), 1916-1918 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Nestor Kaufmoy Letters (translations), 1916-1918 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Harry Gabriel Letters, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Harry Gabriel Letters, ca. 1917 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Harry Gabriel Letters (Feb.-Aug.), 1918 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Harry Gabriel Letters (Sept.-Dec.), 1918 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Harry Gabriel Letters, ca. 1918 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Harry Gabriel Letters, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Harry Gabriel Letters, ca. 1919 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Harry Gabriel Military Papers, 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Harry Gabriel Diary and Transcription (Oct.-Nov.), 1919 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Newspaper Clippings re Harry Gabriel, 1918-1919, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1918-1921, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Photographs, 1917-1925 (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
- Negatives, ca. 1917 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Miscellaneous Printed Material (Box 1, Folder 17-18)